

# Tiru Dehariya

## **Professional Summary**

Versatile content writer with about five years of remarkable performance in researching, writing, editing, and proofreading diverse content. Willing to work in a creative and challenging environment of digital content creation and marketing to produce unique, captivating, error-free work.

## Work History

### **EC-Council - Content Writer**

Hyderabad , India 02/2019 - Current

- Utilised exceptional writing, blogging, editing, and proofreading skills to produce unique and engaging content.
- Used tools (such as Grammarly, Yoast, Headline Analyzer) to generate and maintain quality content.
- Managed ad hoc tasks efficiently within the competing deadlines.
- Developed and edited high-quality content, ranging from press releases, website content, social media posts, EDMs, infographics, banners, scripts, transcriptions, to various other forms.
- Performed thorough research and analysis into assigned topics.
- Wrote advertising material (such as brochures, flyers, podcasts) for use by product promotion.
- Assisted in white paper generation and case study creation to increase website traffic.
- Produced creative content to promote brand messages that capture interest of target audience and bring lead conversion.
- Been a key player in problem-solving activities to support teamwork.

### Freelancer - Freelance Content Writer

Bhopal, India

10/2016 - 01/2019

- Analyzed project requirements and adopted different writing styles for projects to create unique copies.
- Collaborated with marketing managers and several product managers in development of content, building the right pitch with brand marketing strategies.
- Collaborated with different business units and digital marketing team in completing all phases of client projects from planning, researching, content creation, quality check to on-time delivery.
- Extended unique copy options for clients to fit various message and

dehariya.tiru@gmail.com 995 960 0947 Bhopal, India 462041

#### Skills

- Unique content creation
- News writing
- Script writing
- Technical writing
- Promotional marketing and advertising
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- Content strategy and marketing
- Social Media Marketing (SMM)
- Editing and proofreading skills
- Language proficiency
- Organizational and management skills

#### Education

06/2011

Laxmi Narain College Of Technology Excellence

Bhopal

Bachelor Of Engineering: Information Technology

marketing objectives.

• Worked on several niches, ranging from healthcare, women-oriented, technical topics, digital marketing, cybersecurity, and others.

# Blueberry Digital Labs - SEO Executive

Hyderabad, India 02/2016 - 09/2016

- Conducted off-page search engine optimization with backlinking, keyword research, and keyword expansion abilities.
- Handled content management systems (such as WordPress)
- Created proactive SEO strategies to compete with competitors and meet company's needs.
- Monitored performance of SEO strategies and statistics using tools (such as SEMRush, Google Adwords, Google Analytics, Moz) to identify areas of improvement.
- Updated knowledge base with ongoing and upcoming market trends and algorithm updates of top search engines.
- Reviewed and optimized company's sites to improve keyword targeting URL strategies, and webpage architecture.
- Conducted social media marketing to build a greater community.